export const GOVERNMENTA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Government as an institution of the state is defined as a body which",
A: "conducts elections for the country",
B: "makes, enforces and interprets laws for the state",
C: "hires and trains political leaders",
D: "makes and interprets laws",
answer: "B. makes, enforces and interprets laws for the state",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The study of government in school is important because the students can",
A: "be assisted by political leaders",
B: "learn about their rights",
C: "quality for elections",
D: "be nominated for a trip abroad",
answer: "B. learn about their rights",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The primary function of government in a state is to",
A: "maintain law and order",
B: "provide transport services",
C: "engage in campaigns and rallies",
D: "imprison criminals",
answer: "A. maintain law and order",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The functions of the state are achieved through",
A: "political socialization",
B: "separation of powers",
C: "organs of government",
D: "diplomatic means",
answer: "C. organs of government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A unique feature of a state is",
A: "information",
B: "anarchy",
C: "organized laws",
D: "direct democracy",
answer: "C. organized laws",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Ability to enforce obedience is known as",
A: "legitimacy",
B: "power",
C: "influence",
D: "fame",
answer: "B. power",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A major source of political power is",
A: "election",
B: "force",
C: "influence",
D: "ombudsman",
answer: "B. force",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Power is transferred into authority through",
A: "force",
B: "legitimacy",
C: "judiciary",
D: "sovereignty",
answer: "B. legitimacy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Political authority is the",
A: "legitimate right to exercise political power",
B: "ability to control political behaviour",
C: "right to participate in political campaigns",
D: "right to form political parties",
answer: "A. legitimate right to exercise political power",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The extent to which the citizens accept the institutions, official and activities of government is known as",
A: "authority",
B: "permission",
C: "legitimacy",
D: "power",
answer: "C. legitimacy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The concept of sovereignty was propounded by",
A: "Adam Smith",
B: "Jeremy Bentham",
C: "Kari Marx",
D: "Jean Bodin",
answer: "D. Jean Bodin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Popular sovereignty belongs to the",
A: "immigrants",
B: "electorate",
C: "cabinet",
D: "legislature",
answer: "B. electorate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following factors places limitation to the application of Sovereignty in a state?",
A: "Civil service",
B: "International laws",
C: "Political culture",
D: "Political parties",
answer: "B. International laws",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Democracy originated from",
A: "Greece",
B: "Britain",
C: "USA",
D: "Germany",
answer: "A. Greece",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following is a basic principle of democracy? Rule by",
A: "the majority and the protection of the minority",
B: "the wealthy few",
C: "the minority at the expense of the majority",
D: "two political parties",
answer: "A. the majority and the protection of the minority",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The concept of political culture was introduced by",
A: "Friendrich Engels",
B: "Abraham Lincoln",
C: "Harold Laski",
D: "Gabriel Almond",
answer: "D. Gabriel Almond",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following is a component of political culture?",
A: "Injunction",
B: "Congnitive orientation",
C: "Mandamus",
D: "Harbeas corpus",
answer: "B. Cognitive orientation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The teaching and learning of political culture is known as political",
A: "participation",
B: "socialization",
C: "administration",
D: "development",
answer: "B. socialization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following political concepts promotes sharing and cooperation in a society?",
A: "Aristocracy",
B: "Capitalism",
C: "Communalism",
D: "Oligarchy",
answer: "C. Communalism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following can contribute to political socialization?",
A: "Gerrymandering",
B: "Tourism",
C: "Diplomatic immunity",
D: "Terrorism",
answer: "B. Tourism (Exposure to different cultures and societies contributes to political socialization.)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is true about a capitalist state?",
A: "Private individuals control the economy",
B: "The workers are not exploited",
C: "Government controls the means of production",
D: "There is no class struggle",
answer: "A. Private individuals control the economy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The highest stage of socialism is",
A: "oligarchy",
B: "capitalism",
C: "totalitarianism",
D: "communism",
answer: "D. communism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Foreign domination by a group of people for social and economic benefits is known as",
A: "nationalism",
B: "colonialism",
C: "feudalism",
D: "constitutionalism",
answer: "B. colonialism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A communist system recognizes",
A: "class division",
B: "the need for individual",
C: "human capital",
D: "division of labour",
answer: "D. division of labour",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following is the lowest in the hierarchy of a feudal system?",
A: "Lords",
B: "Serfs",
C: "Knights",
D: "Nobles",
answer: "B. Serfs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A common feature of feudalism is",
A: "hierarchical land ownership between the lords and the serfs",
B: "private ownership of the means of production and distribution",
C: "separation of powers",
D: "fusion of powers",
answer: "A. hierarchical land ownership between the lords and the serfs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. An open market economy is a unique feature of",
A: "welfarism",
B: "socialism",
C: "feudalism",
D: "capitalism",
answer: "D. capitalism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following political system discourages socialism?",
A: "fascism",
B: "feudalism",
C: "communalism",
D: "welfarism",
answer: "A. fascism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The manor is a unique feature of",
A: "feudalism",
B: "monarchy",
C: "totalitarianism",
D: "communism",
answer: "A. feudalism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The principle of rule of law was popularized by",
A: "Gabriel Almond",
B: "Charles Montesquieu",
C: "Jean Bodin",
D: "A.V.Dicey",
answer: "D. A.V.Dicey",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The body charged with the responsibility of preparing a new constitution in a country is the",
A: "electoral commission",
B: "constitutuent assembly",
C: "judicial service commission",
D: "electoral college",
answer: "B. constitutuent assembly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The institution connected with law adjudication is the",
A: "judiciary",
B: "police",
C: "government",
D: "executive",
answer: "A. judiciary",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is not a characteristic of confederation?",
A: "The right to secede is allowed",
B: "Sovereignty resides in the centre",
C: "The centre and units agree before taking decisions",
D: "Autonomous units are more powerful than the centre",
answer: "B. Sovereignty resides in the centre",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following is a function of a head of state?",
A: "Settles cases",
B: "Arbitrates electoral petitions",
C: "Creates new constitutions",
D: "Receives foreign dignitaries",
answer: "D. Receives foreign dignitaries",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Citizenship can be changed through",
A: "proclamation",
B: "residence",
C: "renunciation",
D: "announcement",
answer: "C. renunciation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. On which of the following platforms do political parties mainly present their manifestoes to the electorate?",
A: "Campaigns and rallies",
B: "The state-controlled mass media",
C: "Public lectures",
D: "Inter-party debates",
answer: "A. Campaigns and rallies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In a two-party system, only two political parties",
A: "exist in the country",
B: "dominate the political scene",
C: "register their members",
D: "undertake political education",
answer: "B. dominate the political scene",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following is not a form of proportional representation?",
A: "Alternative vote",
B: "Second ballot",
C: "List system",
D: "Plurality system",
answer: "D. Plurality system (Plurality systems do not use proportional representation methods.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The efficiency of public corporations can be enhanced through",
A: "increased production of goods",
B: "appointment of staff based on patronage",
C: "frequent redeployment of staff",
D: "less government interference",
answer: "D. less government interference",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A chief could be deposed in the pre-colonial era if he",
A: "violated the written constitution",
B: "persistently neglected the advice of his elders",
C: "refused to collect taxes for the British Governor",
D: "married too many wives",
answer: "B. persistently neglected the advice of his elders",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A common feature in a pre-colonial centralized state was",
A: "loyalty to one political superior",
B: "absence of single superior political authority",
C: "the existence of an autocratic rule",
D: "existence of separation of powers",
answer: "A. loyalty to one political superior",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Under the British Crown Colony system of administration, the head of the executive council was the",
A: "Governor-General",
B: "Head of government business",
C: "Speaker",
D: "Prime minister",
answer: "A. Governor-General",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Taxation as a feature of Indirect Rule served as a",
A: "source of revenue for colonial administration",
B: "system of modernizing chieftaincy",
C: "policy of making the local people poor",
D: "means to ridicule the chiefs",
answer: "A. source of revenue for colonial administration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One effect of the French policy of Assimilation was that it",
A: "made all French West Africans French citizens",
B: "increased nationalist activities in French West Africa",
C: "delayed nationalism in French West Africa",
D: "expanded education into the interior of French West Africa",
answer: "A. made all French West Africans French citizens",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The late development of nationalism in French West Africa was due to",
A: "absorption of French colonial ex-servicemen into the French army",
B: "implemented government policies",
C: "collected and spent taxes and rates",
D: "were sources of consultation on customary affairs",
answer: "A. absorption of French colonial ex-servicemen into the French army",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The first British West African country to practise the elective principle was",
A: "Nigeria",
B: "The Gambia",
C: "Sierra Leone",
D: "Ghana",
answer: "A. Nigeria",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The first Pan-West African political organization formed by the educated elite in the early twentieth century was the",
A: "Aborigines’Rights Protection Society (ARPS)",
B: "National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA)",
C: "West African Students’Union (WASU)",
D: "West African Youth League (WAYL)",
answer: "B. National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following is a process in the transition from military to civil rule?",
A: "Appointment of an Attorney -General",
B: "Suspension of the constitution",
C: "Setting up of a Constituent Assembly",
D: "Non-implementation of development plans",
answer: "C. Setting up of a Constituent Assembly",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The objective of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) is to",
A: "promote economic development among member states",
B: "achieve unity",
C: "establish political unification of West Africa",
D: "eradicate all forms of racism in West Africa",
answer: "A. promote economic development among member states",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]